

CONTACT

- +92 313 5287178
- hamidishaq476@gmail.com
- Islamabad, Pakistan
- in hamid-ishaq-368a18236
- Hamidlshaq

EDUCATION

2021 - Present FAST NUCES

• BS Computer Science

2018 - 2020 PAKTURK MAARIF INTL.

- FSc Pre-Engineering
- Marks: 80% Grade: A

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Python
- C/C++/C#, .NET
- Java, JavaFX
- HTML, CSS, JS, JQUERY
- WORDPRESS, BOOTSTRAP
- SQL, MySQL, SQLite
- KOTLIN ANDROID DEV
- Firebase

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Communication Skills
- GitHub VCS
- Presentation Skills
- Agile Development

HAMID ISHAQ

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am a dedicated BS student majoring in Computer Science, currently in my 7th semester. With experience in front-end development from a remote internship and as a Lab Demonstrator for Computer Networking at my university, I possess strong skills in software development and diverse programming languages. My career interests center around Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning while maintaining proficiency in web development, android development and database technologies. Known for my punctuality, communication, and presentation skills, I am committed to delivering high-quality work in all endeavours.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FAST NUCES

Lab Demonstrator, Computer Networks Lab

FEB 2024 -- MAY 2024

- Assisted instructor in lab sessions and graded student assignments.
- Emphasized Cisco Packet Tracing and Socket Programming in the curriculum.
- Facilitated hands-on learning and troubleshooting to enhance student understanding of networking concepts.

Interns.pk

Front-End Development Internee

OCT 2023 - NOV 2023

- Developed and maintained user-facing websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress.
- Created UI components with reusable codes for a better user experience.
- Used version control systems such as Git and Repl.it to manage source code repositories in a team environment.

PROJECTS

SmartScholar LMS using Entity Framework Apri 2024 - May 2024

• Developed a University LMS using ASP.NET and Entity Framework

PetConnect Mobile Application

Mar 2024 - April 2024

 Designed and Implemented an Android App for Pets Marketplace using Firebase and Web Services that includes Appointment Booking and FCM

MentorMe Mobile Application

Mar 2024 - April 2024

• Implemented the Prototype of an Android App for Mentors

PetConnect Desktop Application & Website Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

 Designed and Implemented a Desktop Application using JavaFX and Website using WordPress for Pets Marketplace

University DBMS on ASP.NET

April 2023 - May 2023

Brick Breaker Game Dev. in Assembly

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

DBMS using different Tree Data Structures

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022